export const chapter = "Chapter - 9: Force,Work and Emergency  ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "What is force in physics?",
          optionA: "The ability to do work",
          optionB: "The energy of an object",
          optionC: "A push or pull acting on an object",
          correctAnswer: "A push or pull acting on an object",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which of the following is an effect of force on an object?",
          optionA: "Changing its color",
          optionB: "Changing its shape and size",
          optionC: "Changing its temperature",
          correctAnswer: "Changing its shape and size",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which type of force occurs between two objects not in contact with each other?",
          optionA: "Friction force",
          optionB: "Contact force",
          optionC: "Non-contact force",
          correctAnswer: "Non-contact force",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the force that opposes motion when two surfaces in contact slide or roll against each other?",
          optionA: "Gravity",
          optionB: "Friction",
          optionC: "Tension",
          correctAnswer: "Friction",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which category of friction is demonstrated when driving a car across a road surface?",
          optionA: "Static friction",
          optionB: "Sliding friction",
          optionC: "Rolling friction",
          correctAnswer: "Rolling friction",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What force pulls objects down towards the center of the Earth?",
          optionA: "Magnetic force",
          optionB: "Electric force",
          optionC: "Gravity",
          correctAnswer: "Gravity",
        },
        {
          question: "In scientific terms, what is work defined as?",
          optionA: "The ability to exert force",
          optionB: "Force acting on an object to move it across a distance",
          optionC: "The change in an object's shape",
          correctAnswer:
            "Force acting on an object to move it across a distance",
        },
        {
          question:
            "If an object changes its shape or size when a force is applied, is work considered to be done?",
          optionA: "Yes, always",
          optionB: "No, never",
          optionC: "Yes, but only in certain situations",
          correctAnswer: "Yes, but only in certain situations",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the formula for work in physics?",
          optionA: "Work = Mass x Acceleration",
          optionB: "Work = Force x Distance",
          optionC: "Work = Energy / Time",
          correctAnswer: "Work = Force x Distance",
        },
        {
          question: "What is energy defined as in physics?",
          optionA: "The ability to do work",
          optionB: "The force applied to an object",
          optionC: "The speed of an object in motion",
          correctAnswer: "The ability to do work",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Friction is a force that occurs when two surfaces in contact slide or roll against each other. This force is always in the direction opposite to that of the ________ of the object.",
          optionA: "Acceleration",
          optionB: "Motion",
          optionC: "Inertia",
          correctAnswer: "Motion",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Gravity is the force that pulls objects down towards the center of the Earth. Without gravity, objects, including people, would be floating around in ________.",
          optionA: "Air",
          optionB: "Space",
          optionC: "Water",
          correctAnswer: "Space",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In scientific terms, work is defined as force acting on an object to move it across a ________.",
          optionA: "Dimension",
          optionB: "Distance",
          optionC: "Density",
          correctAnswer: "Distance",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Energy is the ability to do work and exists in different forms such as solar energy, wind energy, electrical energy, hydro energy, and ________ energy.",
          optionA: "Magnetic",
          optionB: "Heat",
          optionC: "Kinetic",
          correctAnswer: "Heat",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Wind energy moves the blades of a windmill, which in turn moves machines called turbines that are used to generate ________.",
          optionA: "Light",
          optionB: "Heat",
          optionC: "Electricity",
          correctAnswer: "Electricity",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Hydro energy is the energy of moving water and is used to generate ________.",
          optionA: "Heat",
          optionB: "Light",
          optionC: "Electricity",
          correctAnswer: "Electricity",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The force that opposes motion when solid, fluid, or gaseous surfaces meet is known as ________.",
          optionA: "Tension",
          optionB: "Friction",
          optionC: "Inertia",
          correctAnswer: "Friction",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The energy we get from the sun is called ________ energy. Plants use this energy to prepare their food through photosynthesis.",
          optionA: "Solar",
          optionB: "Heat",
          optionC: "Electrical",
          correctAnswer: "Solar",
        },
        {
          question:
            "If an object changes its shape or size when a force is applied to it, work is said to be done. However, if the object does not move, then no ________ is done.",
          optionA: "Power",
          optionB: "Energy",
          optionC: "Work",
          correctAnswer: "Work",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Sources of energy include the sun, wind, water, and ________.",
          optionA: "Earth",
          optionB: "Fuels",
          optionC: "Air",
          correctAnswer: "Fuels",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Friction is a force that occurs when two surfaces in contact slide or roll against each other and is always in the direction opposite to that of the motion of the object.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Gravity is a force that pulls objects up away from the center of the Earth.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Work is defined as force acting on an object to move it across a dimension.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Energy is the ability to do work and exists in various forms such as solar energy, wind energy, electrical energy, hydro energy, and heat energy.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Rolling friction is the force that opposes motion when solid, fluid, or gaseous surfaces meet.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Hydro energy is the energy of moving water and is not used to generate electricity.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Static friction is the type of friction demonstrated when driving a car across a road surface.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The force that opposes motion when two surfaces in contact slide or roll against each other is called tension.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Coniferous trees grow at a height of 1600 meters or above in the Himalayan and in the Nilgiri Hills in the South.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The areas which have heavy rainfall and hot climate are called tropical, and the trees which remain in leaf throughout the year are called deciduous trees.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
